

Web Developer

http://samliu.me

Phone: +886975293788 Email: sliu178@gmail.com Skype: sam-cblock

OBJECTIVE

I am seeking a creative and challenging position in web development that utilize my skills and further expand my technical skills.

SUMMARY

A well rounded web developer with over five years of experience in analyzing, developing and managing websites and web applications. Constantly learning and self-directed with the ability to work independently and as part of a team.

My ability to research, analyze and solve problems with a great instinct, determination and business sense can be an instant benefit to your organization.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: PHP, Python, Javascript, Objective C, HTML

Database: MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB

Technologies & Tools: memcache, Codelgniter, Django, jQuery, smarty

Operating Systems: CentOS, FreeBSD, Windows, Mac OS

Web servers: Apache, lighttpd, nginx
Data Mining: google analytic, kontagent

Version Control: Git, Mercurial

LANGUAGES

Fluent in English and Mandarin Chinese.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SOHO, Saturday LLC., Taipei, Taiwan — 2011~recent

Audio-Technica Taiwan (http://www.audio-technica.com.tw/)
 Redesigned and developed website using PHP, MySQL,Javascript,jQuery.

Phone: +886975293788 Email: sliu178@gmail.com Skype: sam-cblock

- Jellybird Company (http://www.jellybirdcompany.com/)
 Developed website using Wordpress, PHP, MySQL, Javascript, jQuery.
- Tarot Yearcycle (http://itunes.apple.com/tw/app/ta-luo-liu-nian/id477137482?mt=8)
 Developed iOS application for apple app store

Software Developer, meeya Inc., Taipei, Taiwan — 2008~2011

- Developed "social group" (similar to facebook's page) function for social website meeya.cc
- Developed a PHP, MySQL based web game called "island7" for social website meeya.cc
- Developed facebook social application solutions using PHP,Python Django, MySQL for internet marketing campaigns.
- Lead backend developer for facebook social game "StoreCity" using PHP, MySQL and MongoDB database using AMFPHP to communicate with flash game client.
- Lead developer for social game "StoreCity" cross platform deployment. Deployed on mixi japan, mobage japan, Hyves Nederlands and Nasza Klasa Poland using OpenSocial protocol.

Software Developer, CoreLight Technology Co., Ltd., Taipei, Taiwan — 2007~2008

- Maintained, Bug fixed and added features to the LMS(Learning management system) platform(built using PHP).
- Implemented blog system & live broadcast channel into Shih Chien University Library website using PHP and MySQL on windows NT.

EDUCATION

University of Auckland, New Zealand — BSc, Computer Science 2001~2003